Leah: What is Test Driven Development?
The Test Driven Development approach
creates test cases to specify and
validate what the code will do.
Test cases for each function are ‘created
and tested first’ before the actual
development of the application or program
and if the test fails, new code is written.
Chris: TDD is based on 3
main principles which are:
1.
Do not write any production code unless it
is to make a ‘failing unit test’ ‘pass’.
2.
Do not write any more of a ‘unit
test’ than is sufficient to ‘fail’.
3.
Do not write any more production code than is
sufficient to ‘pass’ the ‘one failing unit test’.
Leah: Since points 1 and 3 are both
involve “refactoring” of code, this can
be simplified to ‘2 points’ which are:
1.
Write only enough of a unit test to fail.
2.
Write only enough production code
to make the failing unit test, pass.
So how is this done in practice?
Chris: Step 1
A developer writes the ‘test case’
without any code in front of them.
This may sound tricky, but it ensures that the
developer understands the functionality required.
The test case is not biased to show the ‘code’
works, rather to test the ‘expected feature’.
In this step you will try to ‘run the
test’ and as the ‘actual code’ has not
been written, your test will ‘fail’.
Leah: Step 2
The developer writes only the
minimum required code, to pass the
test case, that just ‘got failed’.
This becomes a challenging activity
for developers who are used to writing
code for the ‘full module’ in one go.
The “Just enough” code concept, helps in
ensuring that no extra bit of code is added.
The developer again runs the test
case, and make sure it passes.
Step 3
Chris: The developers ‘refactor’ the
code, to ensure the functionality
is intact and code is refined.
In steps 1 and 2 the focus is to write code
only, whereas other important points for
efficient design, maintainable code etc.
are not considered.
Once the test ‘passes’ the developer will check
for any ‘unnecessary code’ which can be removed.
Leah: While TDD may seem like it adds
extra work to the development of software,
it constrains the complexity and effort
which is put into the initial coding.
Chris: This comes with several benefits such as:
• Reducing rework time and enhancing productivity.
• Allowing for quick exploration of bugs and errors.
• Leah: Making it quick to get feedback,
and encouraging knowledge sharing and
collaboration, so that anyone should be
able to make a start on any section of code.
• Allowing programmers to easily change
overarching program architecture and
encouraging cleaner program design.
• Chris: It results in the creation of extensive
code that is flexible and easy to maintain.
• It also means that requirements in the design
spec are addressed directly during implementation.